Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and you've been with us for a little while.
我是Catherine，你跟我们在一起已经有一段时间了。
You've probably heard some of our interview series already.
你可能已经听过我们的一些访谈系列了。
Well this is one of the later episodes in that series.
嗯，这是那个系列中较晚的一集。
That's right.
没错。
We're at part number nine.
我们现在是第九部分。
We're reaching the end of our interview and on this occasion we're going to ask our employer
我们正在接近访谈的尾声，这次我们要问我们的雇主
a little bit of more information about the company and more importantly about the job.
一些关于公司的更多信息，更重要的是关于这份工作。
Well this is a very important step.
嗯，这是非常重要的一步。
Like you say, it's at the end of the interview so we're going to find out more details about
就像你说的，这是在访谈的结尾，所以我们要了解更多关于
the job.
这份工作的细节。
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue.
让我们来听听今天的对话。
We'll be back in a moment to talk more about it.
我们一会儿回来再讨论。
Could you tell me a little about the organization?
你能告诉我一些关于这个组织的情况吗？
For example, how big is your office here?
比如，你们这里的办公室有多大？
Well in total we have around 150 employees based in Hong Kong with another 400 in our
嗯，我们在香港总共有大约150名员工，另外还有400名在
head office in Beijing.
北京的总部。
The news desk staff in Hong Kong has around 80 staff.
香港的新闻编辑室大约有80名员工。
I see.
我明白了。
And how about the working hours?
那工作时间呢？
Well as you know Rebecca, in journalism work hours are not exactly nine to five.
嗯，Rebecca，你知道，在新闻行业，工作时间不完全是朝九晚五。
You could be on call at any time but we do have to work very unsociable hours at times.
你可能随时待命，但我们确实有时需要工作非常不规律的时间。
Well I'm used to that Mr Parsons.
嗯，我已经习惯了，Parsons先生。
So that's not really a shock for me.
所以这对我来说并不意外。
Good.
很好。
As long as you understand that.
只要你明白这一点。
And when do you need to fill the vacancy Mr Parsons?
那你们什么时候需要填补这个空缺呢，Parsons先生？
Yesterday but no.
昨天，但不行。
We're hoping to start from the beginning of next month.
我们希望从下个月初开始。
That sounds like deal.
听起来不错。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So it's obviously a very difficult job and she asked some very key questions.
所以这显然是一份非常困难的工作，她问了一些非常关键的问题。
So why don't we take a look at a couple of the words and phrases used there on Language
那我们为什么不看看在“语言要点”中用到的一些单词和短语呢？
Takeaway.
语言要点。
Language Takeaway.
The first word that we have here for Language Takeaway is workforce.
我们在“语言要点”中第一个词是workforce。
That's right a workforce.
没错，workforce。
The company's workforce.
公司的员工队伍。
And that basically means all the employees that we have working for us.
这基本上意味着所有为我们工作的员工。
That might not be in one office.
可能不都在一个办公室。
Many companies have two, three, even a hundred offices.
很多公司有两个、三个，甚至一百个办公室。
So the workforce means all the people who work for the company combined.
所以workforce指的是所有为公司工作的人的总和。
That's right.
没错。
So a workforce.
所以是workforce。
And well she asked about the workforce and well it's obviously a pretty big company.
嗯，她问了关于员工队伍的问题，显然这是一家相当大的公司。
150 employees.
150名员工。
But he also mentioned that the news desk staff in Hong Kong comprises around 80 people or
但他也提到香港的新闻编辑室员工大约有80人，或者说
80 staff.
80名员工。
So this verb to comprise or in this case it comprises means to make up or to account for.
所以这个动词to comprise，或者在这个例子中它表示comprises，意思是组成或占。
It's a very nice word to say it accounts for, it makes up, it's the total.
这是一个很好的词，表示占、组成、是总数。
It's the total right.
是总数，对吧。
So in this case the news desk staff has 80 people.
所以在这个例子中，新闻编辑室员工有80人。
That's a very easy way to say it.
这是一种非常简单的说法。
But we could say it comprises 80 people.
但我们可以说它comprises 80人。
It sounds a bit better.
听起来更好一些。
That's right.
没错。
Very good.
非常好。
So now obviously she's going to be a reporter or a journalist and he said that she should
所以现在显然她将成为一名记者或新闻工作者，他说她应该
be on call at any time.
随时待命。
Okay.
好的。
On call is a phrase that we often hear with jobs like journalism but also medicine.
On call是一个我们经常在新闻工作等职业中听到的短语，还有医学领域。
So doctors have to be on call very often.
所以医生经常需要on call。
This means that you don't have to be in the office but you have to be available to come
这意味着你不必在办公室，但你必须随时可以来
into the office.
办公室。
So when someone calls you and they say we have an emergency you have to be available.
所以当有人打电话给你说我们有紧急情况时，你必须有空。
That's right.
没错。
And you see it in movies all the time.
你在电影里经常看到这种情况。
You know doctors are on call and maybe they're already sleeping or maybe they're out I don't
你知道，医生在on call，也许他们已经在睡觉，或者他们可能在外面，我不知道
know playing soccer with their kids and they receive a phone call and they have to go to
和孩子们踢足球，然后他们接到电话，必须立刻去
the hospital in that moment.
医院。
It's because they're on call.
那是因为他们在on call。
That's because they're on call.
Very good.
非常好。
And so obviously this is a very difficult thing for someone.
所以显然这对某人来说是一件非常困难的事情。
And he explains that the work has very unsociable hours at times.
他解释说，这份工作有时工作时间非常不规律。
Okay so you can say that the hours are unsociable.
好的，所以你可以说工作时间是unsociable。
You can also say that a person is unsociable.
你也可以说一个人是unsociable。
It basically means that it's not very convenient for being a social person or for going out
这基本上意味着它不太方便社交，或者不方便出去
with friends and having many events to go to or fun things to do in your personal life.
和朋友一起，参加很多活动，或者在个人生活中做有趣的事情。
That's right.
没错。
So if a person is unsociable it means that maybe that person is not very outgoing or
所以，如果一个人不善社交，那可能意味着这个人不太外向，或者
maybe is always angry or grumpy so that person doesn't get along well with others.
可能总是生气或脾气暴躁，所以这个人不太容易和别人相处。
Right.
对。
So in this case it doesn't mean that it's a grumpy job.
所以在这种情况下，这并不意味着这是一份让人脾气暴躁的工作。
It just means that because she might have to work at night very often or on the weekends
这只是说，因为她可能经常需要在晚上或周末工作，
it's very hard to have a social life.
所以很难有社交生活。
That's right.
没错。
Okay so obviously this job is very difficult but in the end she was really happy with it
好的，显然这份工作很困难，但最后她对此非常满意，
and she said that sounds ideal, her starting time.
她说她的开始时间听起来很理想。
So something is ideal if it's perfect or great or the top.
所以，如果某件事是理想的，那就意味着它完美、很棒或是最好的。
That's right.
没错。
Many people talk about the ideal job, right?
很多人会谈论理想的工作，对吧？
The perfect job.
完美的工作。
So that's the job that you have in your mind when you think of what is the best.
所以，那是你心里想到的最好的工作时所想象的样子。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe my ideal job is different from your ideal job.
所以，也许我的理想工作和你的理想工作不一样。
That's right.
没错。
So you have ideal jobs or your ideal house or your dream house.
所以，你有理想的工作，或者理想的房子，或者梦想中的房子。
Your ideal husband.
你理想的丈夫。
That's right.
没错。
So ideal, idealism.
所以，理想，理想主义。
So why don't we listen to the dialogue again.
那么，我们为什么不重新听一遍对话呢？
Let's review what Rebecca and Mr. Parsons talked about and we'll be back in a little
我们来回顾一下Rebecca和Parsons先生谈了什么，我们一会儿回来
bit with Fluency Builder.
进行流利度训练。
Could you tell me a little about the organization?
你能跟我介绍一下这个组织吗？
For example, how big is your office here?
比如，你们这里的办公室有多大？
Well, in total we have around 150 employees based in Hong Kong with another 400 in our
嗯，我们总共有大约150名员工在香港，另外还有400名在
head office in Beijing.
北京的总部。
The news desk staff in Hong Kong has around 80 staff.
香港的新闻编辑室大约有80名员工。
I see.
我明白了。
And how about the working hours?
那工作时间呢？
Well, as you know Rebecca, in journalism work hours are not exactly 9 to 5.
嗯，Rebecca，你知道，新闻行业的工作时间不是严格的朝九晚五。
You could be on call at any time, but we do have to work very unsociable hours at times.
你随时可能被叫去工作，但我们确实有时需要在不合常理的时间工作。
Well, I'm used to that Mr. Parsons.
嗯，Parsons先生，我已经习惯了。
So that's not really a shock for me.
所以这对我来说并不意外。
Good.
很好。
As long as you understand that.
只要你明白这一点就好。
And when do you need to fill the vacancy Mr. Parsons?
那你们什么时候需要填补这个空缺呢，Parsons先生？
Yesterday, but no.
昨天，但不行。
We're hoping to start from the beginning of next month.
我们希望从下个月初开始。
That sounds ideal.
那听起来很理想。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we have four phrases for you prepared on Fluency Builder.
所以现在我们为你们准备了四个短语，用于流利度训练。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
This first phrase is something that we say all the time in English, but I think a lot
第一个短语是我们英语中经常说的，但我认为很多
of learners make mistakes when they use it.
学习者在用它时会犯错。
The phrase is how about.
这个短语是“how about”。
That's right.
没错。
So you see that Rebecca was listening to what Mr. Parsons said and she said, and how about
所以你看，Rebecca在听Parsons先生说话，然后她说，“那工作时间
the working hours?
呢？”
So this is a way to say, and what are the working hours?
所以这是一种表达“那工作时间是什么？”的方式。
But basically it's a way to continue the conversation.
但基本上，这是一种继续对话的方式。
You can say this in many different ways, but it basically means, and what about?
你可以用很多不同的方式说这个，但它基本上意思是“那……呢？”
Or, please tell me about.
或者“请告诉我关于……”。
That's right.
没错。
Now remember that many English learners mistake the phrase how about as if they were saying,
现在记住，很多英语学习者会误用“how about”这个短语，好像他们在说
how are you?
“how are you？”
Or how is it?
或者“how is it？”
No.
不。
You have to be following someone else in the conversation.
你必须在对话中接着别人的话来说。
So for example, I could say, you know what?
所以，比如，我可以说，“你知道吗？”
I'm going to have a hamburger with bacon.
“我要吃一个培根汉堡。”
How about you Marco?
“你呢，Marco？”
What are you going to eat?
“你要吃什么？”
How about you buy me a cheeseburger?
“你请我吃一个芝士汉堡怎么样？”
Okay, so this is basically a way of saying, okay, well maybe I'll have a cheeseburger
好的，所以这基本上是一种表达“好吧，也许我会吃一个芝士汉堡”
or what are you going to have?
或者“你要吃什么？”的方式。
So now it's important to say, don't ever make this question.
所以现在重要的是要说，永远不要问这个问题。
Don't ever ask, how about your weekend?
永远不要问“how about your weekend？”
No, no, no, no, no.
不，不，不，不，不。
How was your weekend?
“how was your weekend？”
That's right.
没错。
My weekend was great.
我的周末很棒。
How about yours?
你的呢？
That's continuing the conversation saying, mine was good.
这是继续对话，意思是“我的很好。”
How was yours?
“你的怎么样？”
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So what did he say?
那他怎么说？
He said that when they were talking about the work hours, he said that the work hours
他说，当他们讨论工作时间时，他说工作时间
are not exactly nine to five.
并不完全是朝九晚五。
Okay, so this is a kind of a set phrase we use often in English because a lot of people
好的，这是我们在英语中常用的一种固定短语，因为很多人
traditionally have worked from 9am to 5pm.
传统上都是从早上9点工作到下午5点。
They have a break at lunch, then they go home.
他们中午休息一下，然后回家。
That's right.
没错。
So this is a kind of measure for, this is a way to describe traditional working hours
所以这是一种衡量标准，一种描述传统工作时间
or traditional jobs.
或传统工作的方式。
So you can say, yeah, I have a really nice nine to five job.
所以你可以说，嗯，我有一份很不错的朝九晚五的工作。
You could say, I really don't want to work a nine to five job.
你也可以说，我真的不想做朝九晚五的工作。
That's right.
没错。
So you don't want a traditional job where you're working from nine to five.
所以你不想做那种从九点工作到五点的传统工作。
Right.
对。
Most people I think work a little bit longer than that, but this is just a way of saying
我想大多数人工作时间比那要长一点，但这只是一种说法，
a traditional job.
指代传统工作。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Nine to five job.
朝九晚五的工作。
Now, why don't we move on to Rebecca saying that she is used to working long hours or
现在，我们来看看Rebecca说她习惯了长时间工作
being on call.
或随时待命。
Right.
对。
So this construction, to be used to, I'm used to doing this, is a way to say that I already
所以这个结构，“be used to”，我习惯做这个，是一种表达我已经
do this.
在做这件事的方式。
This is my experience or I have the habit of working unusual hours.
这是我的经验，或者我有在非正常时间工作的习惯。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe for example, you live in a very noisy area in your neighborhood and somebody comes
所以比如，你住在一个很吵的社区，有人来
and visits you and they can't sleep because it's so noisy.
拜访你，他们因为太吵而睡不着。
You are used to it.
你已经习惯了。
Oh, you say, Oh, I don't mind.
哦，你会说，哦，我不介意。
I'm used to the noise.
我习惯这噪音了。
But your friend who's visiting is not used to it.
但你的朋友来拜访却不习惯。
Right.
对。
They don't have this noise at home.
他们家里没有这种噪音。
So that's what happens and it can't sleep.
所以就是这样，他们睡不着。
So when you are used to something, you have the habit or you're accustomed to it.
所以当你习惯某件事时，你有这个习惯或者你适应了它。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And what about our last phrase?
那我们的最后一个短语呢？
Our last phrase comes at the end and Rebecca is talking about the start date for this job.
最后一个短语出现在结尾，Rebecca在谈论这份工作的开始日期。
She wants to know, when do you need to fill the vacancy?
她想问，你们需要什么时候填补这个空缺？
Okay.
好的。
To fill the vacancy.
填补空缺。
Now, we have this word vacancy and that means that it's available, right?
现在，我们有“vacancy”这个词，意思是它是可用的，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So vacancy is an available thing.
所以“vacancy”是一个可用的东西。
It could be a vacant place.
可以是一个空位。
Like an apartment?
比如公寓？
Like an apartment.
比如公寓。
In this case, a vacancy in a company.
在这种情况下，是公司里的一个空缺。
That means a job that is available.
意思是一个可用的职位。
That's right.
没错。
So she is asking when she can fill the vacancy.
所以她问什么时候可以填补这个空缺。
So we use the verb fill, to fill a vacancy.
所以我们用动词“fill”，填补空缺。
And this sounds a lot better than saying, Hey, when do I start working here?
这听起来比说“嘿，我什么时候开始在这里工作？”要好得多。
This is a polite way to say, when is the job going to begin?
这是一种礼貌的说法，问工作什么时候开始。
When do you need to fill the vacancy by?
你们需要什么时候填补这个空缺？
I guess another way of saying it would be, when is the starting date?
我想另一种说法是，开始日期是什么时候？
Yes.
是的。
So as we say, also fill the vacancy is a very good option.
所以就像我们说的，“填补空缺”是一个很好的选择。
But don't say, when do I start working?
但不要说“我什么时候开始工作？”
Or when do we start?
或者“我们什么时候开始？”
Yeah, no, we can talk about that in a minute.
嗯，不，我们可以稍后讨论这个。
Let's listen first to our dialogue one more time.
我们先再听一遍对话。
We'll be back shortly.
我们马上回来。
Could you tell me a little about the organization?
你能给我介绍一下这个组织吗？
For example, how big is your office here?
比如，你们这里的办公室有多大？
Well, in total we have around 150 employees based in Hong Kong, with another 400 in our
嗯，我们在香港总共有大约150名员工，另外还有400名在
head office in Beijing.
北京的总部。
The news desk staff in Hong Kong has around 80 staff.
香港的新闻编辑室大约有80名员工。
I see.
我明白了。
And how about the working hours?
那工作时间呢？
Well, as you know, Rebecca, in journalism, work hours are not exactly nine to five.
嗯，Rebecca，你知道，在新闻行业，工作时间不完全是朝九晚五。
You could be on call at any time.
你可能随时待命。
But we do have to work very unsociable hours at times.
但有时我们确实需要在非常不规律的时间工作。
Well, I'm used to that, Mr. Parsons.
嗯，我习惯了，Parsons先生。
So that's not really a shock for me.
所以这对我来说并不意外。
Good, as long as you understand that.
好，只要你明白这一点就行。
And when do you need to fill the vacancy, Mr. Parsons?
那你们需要什么时候填补这个空缺呢，Parsons先生？
Yesterday, but no, we are hoping to start from the beginning of next month.
昨天，但不开玩笑，我们希望从下个月初开始。
That sounds ideal.
听起来很理想。
So talking about working hours, being on call or unsociable working hours, have you ever
所以说到工作时间，比如随时待命或者非正常工作时间，你有没有
had a job where you've had to work maybe through the night?
做过需要通宵工作的活儿？
Yes, I used to work in a movie theater when I was in college.
有啊，我上大学时在电影院工作过。
I had a day job too, so it was kind of a mess.
我白天还有另一份工作，所以搞得一团糟。
I was very unsociable.
我那时候很不合群。
But I worked at a movie theater and I would start working at 6 p.m. or 5 p.m. and I would
但我在电影院工作，通常下午5点或6点开始上班，
work until 2 or 3 a.m.
一直干到凌晨两三点。
And so it was always busiest on Friday and Saturday.
而且周五和周六总是最忙的。
And so I could never go out with my friends.
所以我从来没法跟朋友出去玩。
So while everyone was partying, you were at the movie theater.
所以当大家都在派对狂欢时，你却在电影院。
Exactly.
没错。
Or they would come to the movies and I would sneak in and bring them popcorn.
或者他们会来看电影，我就偷偷溜进去给他们带爆米花。
So these unusual working hours, it's very interesting because usually, although it is
这种不寻常的工作时间很有意思，因为通常虽然
a little bit more of a sacrifice, they usually pay a little bit better, right?
要付出更多牺牲，但工资也会高一些，对吧？
They do and there are some advantages.
确实如此，而且也有一些好处。
It means that you get to sleep in really late.
这意味着你可以睡到很晚。
You don't have to wake up early.
不用早起。
And you have the day off, like the entire day to do something.
而且白天一整天都空闲，可以做点别的事。
Exactly.
没错。
What about you?
你呢？
Have you ever worked unusual hours?
你有没有做过非正常时间的工作？
Yes, yes.
有啊，有啊。
I used to work for a newspaper and obviously people like their newspaper in the mornings.
我以前在一家报社工作，显然人们喜欢早上看报纸。
So bright and early.
所以大清早的。
Bright and early.
大清早的。
We're talking about 6 a.m.
我们说的是早上6点。
So obviously, we would deliver the newspapers around 1 a.m., 2 a.m.
所以显然，我们会在凌晨1点、2点左右送报纸。
From 1 a.m. to about 6 a.m.
从凌晨1点到大约早上6点。
Wow.
哇。
So yeah, pretty unusual and very difficult because, for example, some people, for them,
是啊，非常不寻常，也很辛苦，因为比如有些人觉得
it's great to see the sunrise.
看日出很美好。
I've seen so many sunrises and it's not really romantic for me anymore.
我看过太多日出了，对我来说已经不再浪漫了。
We would call you a night owl.
我们会叫你夜猫子。
Yeah.
是啊。
Someone who's more awake at night.
就是晚上更精神的人。
That's right and I still am.
没错，我现在还是这样。
So we're really interested to know maybe if you had any unusual working hours.
所以我们很想知道，你有没有过什么不寻常的工作时间？
Or do you work a 9 to 5?
还是你做的是一份朝九晚五的工作？
Yeah, do you have a 9 to 5 job?
是啊，你有朝九晚五的工作吗？
So come to our website EnglishPod.com, let us know and we'll see everyone there.
那就来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 告诉我们吧，我们到时候见。
Bye.
再见。
Got it.
明白了。